Not every gift is a blessing.
The Sixth Sense is a mystery, thriller, drama film
directed by M. Night Shyamalan.
Following an unexpected tragedy, child psychologist Malcolm Crowe meets a
nine year old boy named Cole Sear, who is hiding a dark secret.
Malcolm Crowe, played by Bruce Willis.
Cole Sear, played by Haley Joel Osment.
Lynn Sear, played by Toni Collette.
Anna Crowe, played by Olivia Williams.
Vincent Grey, played by Donnie Wahlberg.
Tommy Tammisimo, played by Trevor Morgan.
The Sixth Sense is a 1999 American psychological
thriller film written and directed by M.
Night Shyamalan.
It stars Bruce Willis as a child psychologist whose patient (Haley
Joel Osment) claims he can see and talk to the dead.
Released by Buena Vista Pictures through its Hollywood Pictures label on August 6, 1999, The Sixth Sense was well received by critics and was nominated for six Academy Awards,
including Best Picture, Best Director and Best Original Screenplay for Shyamalan, Best Supporting Actor for Osment, and Best Supporting Actress for Collette.
The film established Shyamalan as a preeminent filmmaker of thrillers and introduced the
cinema public to his traits, most notably his affinity for twist endings.
The film was a commercial success, grossing over $672 million worldwide, becoming the
second-highest-grossing film of 1999 and Shyamalan's highest-grossing film to date.
The film explores themes of dying and death, child abuse,
philadelphia, pennsylvania, sense of guilt, afterlife.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.